

## Alexander HELBOK

Innsbruck/Austria | +43 681 81780037 alexander.helbok@hotmail.com

#### **OVERVIEW**

# I am 19 years old and have a big passion for how and why things work the way they do.

During my high school studies, I discovered my big interest for Physics, especially Astrophysics, which I am pursuing further during my university studies. Besides, my interests stretch from sports to music and all the way to repairing bicycles and solving a Rubik's cube in a matter of seconds.

### **EDUCATION**

EXPERIENCE

Universität Innsbruck

2021 - to date

PHYSICS BACHELOR DEGREE

**GRG1 STUBENBASTEI** 

2012 - 2020

SCIENTIFIC HIGH SCHOOL

TAHATAI COAST SCHOOL

Term 4, October - December 2015

PRIMARY SCHOOL, PAPAMOA, NEW ZEALAND

MUSIKSCHULE OTTAKRING

MUSIC SCHOOL/PIANO LESSONS

2011 - 2021

RADSTUDIO INNSBRUCK

July 2019

SUMMER JOB AS BIKE MECHANIC

STÄDTISCHE KINDERGÄRTEN WIEN

2020 - 2021

SERVING 9 MONTHS OF COMPULSORY CIVIL SERVICE

#### SKILLS

IT - Skills Experienced: LATEX |  $\Lambda$  Unix |  $\Lambda$  Mathematica

Beginner: Python | @ C++

**LANGUAGES** *Native:* Italian & German *Fluent:* English *Beginner:* French

Hobbies Sport: Smooth Mountainbiking | Bouldering | Skiing

Other: Speedcubing | 3D Printing | Scard Magic

#### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Physics bronze medal at the 4<sup>th</sup> International Olympiad of Metropolises in Moscow
- Admission to "Österreichische Studienstiftung" (University Mentoring Program)
- Austrian record holder for the Square-1 cube